Violetta Thijssens

With 5+ years of experience in user-related roles in a corporate environment, I have a keen eye for the user, the product and the bottom line. I am a problem-solver, storyteller, and fast learner. I love to go the extra mile for a project and my team.

SKILLS

RESEARCH

- Usability Testing
- Interviews
- Online & offline Surveys
- Data Analysis
- Web Metrics
- Competitor Research
- Flow Mapping
- · Requirements Analysis

DESIGN

- Prototyping
- Wireframing
- Sketching
- Drawing
- Copy Writing
- Visual Design

TECHNICAL

- Sketch
- InVision
- Axure
- Figma
- Adobe XD
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- SQL
- Python

COLLABORATION

- Team Player
- Communicative
- Strong Presenter
- Agile
- **Project Management**
- Facilitator
- Open to learning

CAREER SUMMARY

Business Analyst H.Essers | Aug 2019-Present

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Requirements analysis
- User experience
- User testing

- · Set up asset management for applications
- · Delivery of upgrade project on budget
- Launch of enterprise-sized application

Business Intelligence Engineer H.Essers | Jan 2019-Aug 2019

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Building user-friendly reports
- Listening to user needs
- Stakeholder management

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Introduction of Power BI
- · Facilitation of teamwork
- · Set up major report on transport deliveries

Senior Data Specialist GfK | May 2018-Jan 2019

RESPONSIBILITIES

- · Data analysis
- Giving presentations
- Follow-up research projects

ACHIEVEMENTS

- · Reduction of data processing for a bimonthly report from one week to one day
- · Improved team collaboration

CRM Specialist Mediahuis | Oct 2016-May 2018

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Web metrics analysis
- **Giving presentations**
- Recommendations for UX

- Ambassador for innovation
- Part of cross-departmental team to improve the customer journey

Market Research Analyst

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Quantitative research
- · Giving presentations

Mediahuis | Aug 2013-Oct 2016

- Usability testing and interviews Set up research on digital customers
 - Research on football players that made headlines for several weeks

EDUCATION

Professional Diploma in UX Design

UX DESIGN INSTITUTE & GLASGOW CALEDONIAN UNIVERSITY | COMPLETED IN 2021

Writing Course

OXFORD UNIVERSITY COMPLETED IN 2020

Team Coach Course

SYNTRA| COMPLETED IN 2020

Diploma in Market and Social Research Practice

MARKET RESEARCH SOCIETY COMPLETED IN 2018

MA in Business, major marketing

CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF LEUVEN COMPLETED IN 2013 GRAPHIC DESIGNER OF STUDENT UNION